<rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/"><channel><title><![CDATA[jsorge.net]]></title>
<description><![CDATA[Christian, husband, dad, developer, batman afficianado.]]></description>
<link>http://jsorge.local</link>
<image><url>http://jsorge.local/favicon.png</url><title>jsorge.net</title><link>http://jsorge.local</link></image>
<generator>Maverick v0.7</generator>
<lastbuilddate>Sun, 03 Jun 2018 21:19:23 GMT</lastbuilddate>
<atom:link href="http://jsorge.local/feed.rss" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
<ttl>60</ttl><item>

<link>http://jsorge.local/2018/05/31/netflix-should-release</link>
<guid ispermalink="false">5b03a67ecebcec05fe03fe5e</guid>
<pubdate>May 31, 2018</pubdate>
<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Netflix should release “VHS Mode”, where watching the same content over and over and over again would degrade the picture over time and eventually snap the tape.</p>
<p>I say this as a parent of boys who are currently on their 1,432nd viewing of the Sarah and Duck show. Make it stop!</p>
]]></content:encoded>
</item><item>

<link>http://jsorge.local/2018/05/31/a-temperature-is</link>
<guid ispermalink="false">5b03a67ecebcec05fe03fe5e</guid>
<pubdate>May 30, 2018</pubdate>
<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>A 104.5 temperature is high, right?</p>
]]></content:encoded>
</item><item>

<link>http://jsorge.local/2018/05/30/this-is-completely</link>
<guid ispermalink="false">5b03a67ecebcec05fe03fe5e</guid>
<pubdate>May 30, 2018</pubdate>
<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>This is completely wild. I have an iPhone that's tethered to my laptop. My laptop is creating a wireless network, which the phone is joined to. And I'm still able to proxy my phone through the laptop using Charles. How does this voodoo work??</p>
<p>🤯</p>
]]></content:encoded>
</item><item>

<link>http://jsorge.local/2018/05/29/i-want-to</link>
<guid ispermalink="false">5b03a67ecebcec05fe03fe5e</guid>
<pubdate>May 28, 2018</pubdate>
<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>I want to take some Markdown text and convert it to HTML, on Linux and calling it from a Vapor 3 project written in Swift. How would I go about doing this?</p>
]]></content:encoded>
</item><item>

<link>http://jsorge.local/2018/05/29/i-should-have</link>
<guid ispermalink="false">5b03a67ecebcec05fe03fe5e</guid>
<pubdate>May 28, 2018</pubdate>
<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>I should have done <em>just a little</em> more digging before posting, and I would have found <a href="https://github.com/vapor-community/markdown">this great library</a> that uses <code>cmark</code> under the hood.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
</item><item>

<link>http://jsorge.local/2018/05/29/i-dont-know</link>
<guid ispermalink="false">5b03a67ecebcec05fe03fe5e</guid>
<pubdate>May 28, 2018</pubdate>
<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>I don’t know much about hockey. But I’m watching the first game of the Stanley Cup Finals and the score is currently 5-4. Isn’t that really high?</p>
]]></content:encoded>
</item><item>

<link>http://jsorge.local/2018/05/28/dang-i-thought</link>
<guid ispermalink="false">5b03a67ecebcec05fe03fe5e</guid>
<pubdate>May 28, 2018</pubdate>
<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Dang, I thought I had my Swift Playground woes fixed in Xcode 9.3.1. But alas, I'm getting the never ending running with this one. I'm just trying to parse a text file!</p>
]]></content:encoded>
</item><item>

<link>http://jsorge.local/2018/05/24/note-to-self</link>
<guid ispermalink="false">5b03a67ecebcec05fe03fe5e</guid>
<pubdate>May 23, 2018</pubdate>
<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Note to self: instead of tweeting about a crazy linter rule at work, petition to have it changed. Make the codebase better rather than whine about it on the interwebs.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
</item><item>

<link>http://jsorge.local/2018/05/23/i-got-recommended</link>
<guid ispermalink="false">5b03a67ecebcec05fe03fe5e</guid>
<pubdate>May 22, 2018</pubdate>
<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>I got recommended to try <a href="https://caddyserver.com">Caddy</a> instead of nginx. I <em>think</em> I have a setup starting to work, but need to figure out how to proxy something from one container to the machine's localhost, and have that display using the machine's port.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
</item><item>
<title><![CDATA[Rebuilding taphouse.io]]></title>
<link>http://jsorge.local/2018/05/22/rebuilding-taphouse-io</link>
<guid ispermalink="false">5b03a67ecebcec05fe03fe5e</guid>
<pubdate>May 21, 2018</pubdate>
<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>A few months ago, when I decided I needed to update JavaScript on my server that ran both my blog and company website, I broke the company site. I wrote it a few years ago using a very early iteration of the <a href="https://sailsjs.com">Sails.js</a> framework. Fast forward to today and I want to bring it back. I also have been wanting to dabble in server-side Swift. <a href="https://vapor.codes">Enter Vapor</a>.</p>
<p>I got the site up and running in Vapor 3 in a few days (last year I had started doing this in Vapor 2, but 3 was just released so the timing was good). I’m a big fan of what the Vapor team is doing and may yet take on a separate project based on Vapor. But that’s for another day.</p>
<p>Today is about Docker. I want my new company site to be housed in a single git repo (✅), and deployable using <a href="https://www.docker.com">Docker</a>. I want to have the vapor app in a container, and <a href="https://www.nginx.com">nginx</a> on the front of it in a separate container. I also want to have SSL on the site, managed by <a href="https://letsencrypt.org">letsencrypt</a>. I’m also hoping to have a dev environment and a production environment (all self contained inside this repo).</p>
<p>This is where my holdup is. I’ve never used Docker, <a href="https://mb.jsorge.net/2018/05/19/i-may-have.html">and have been inundating myself</a> trying to figure it all out.  I want to build this in the open, so I’ll be <a href="https://mb.jsorge.net">microblogging</a> and regular blogging about my progress – however slow it may be.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
</item><item>

<link>http://jsorge.local/2018/05/22/password-v-for</link>
<guid ispermalink="false">5b03a67ecebcec05fe03fe5e</guid>
<pubdate>May 22, 2018</pubdate>
<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><a href="https://blog.agilebits.com/2018/05/22/1password-7-for-mac-the-best-ever/">1Password v7 for the Mac</a> is out today! You should go get it. I've been on the beta for a while now and it's fantastic.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
</item><item>

<link>http://jsorge.local/2018/05/22/madness-is-not</link>
<guid ispermalink="false">5b03a67ecebcec05fe03fe5e</guid>
<pubdate>May 21, 2018</pubdate>
<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Madness is not being able to find out how nginx is serving localhost:8080 when it’s not running and nothing is bound to port 8080.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
</item><item>

<link>http://jsorge.local/2018/05/22/im-going-to</link>
<guid ispermalink="false">5b03a67ecebcec05fe03fe5e</guid>
<pubdate>May 21, 2018</pubdate>
<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>I'm going to call this a successful end to the night: I just got the taphouse.io site running locally in Docker, and could hit it via localhost.</p>
<p>Next is to get it behind nginx locally, which is proving a harder challenge.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
</item><item>

<link>http://jsorge.local/2018/05/22/052735</link>
<guid ispermalink="false">5b03a67ecebcec05fe03fe5e</guid>
<pubdate>May 21, 2018</pubdate>
<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>New post from jsorge.net: <a href="http://jsorge.net/2018/05/21/rebuilding-taphouse-io/">Rebuilding taphouse.io</a></p>
]]></content:encoded>
</item><item>

<link>http://jsorge.local/2018/05/20/i-may-have</link>
<guid ispermalink="false">5b03a67ecebcec05fe03fe5e</guid>
<pubdate>May 19, 2018</pubdate>
<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>I may have hit the point of searching out too much documentation and tutorials for Docker. But I’m nearing the mental place to be able to understand that a container does not always equal a repo. That has been a mental block for me.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
</item><item>

<link>http://jsorge.local/2018/05/19/phase-of-my</link>
<guid ispermalink="false">5b03a67ecebcec05fe03fe5e</guid>
<pubdate>May 19, 2018</pubdate>
<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Phase 1 of my taphouse.io rewrite accomplished: Vapor is complete!</p>
<p>Next up is Docker, Nginx, and actual hosting on a server at <a href="https://m.do.co/c/b54194754f24">Digital Ocean</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
</item><item>

<link>http://jsorge.local/2018/05/19/ive-had-to</link>
<guid ispermalink="false">5b03a67ecebcec05fe03fe5e</guid>
<pubdate>May 18, 2018</pubdate>
<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>I've had to look at the WWDC video for <code>UIPresentationController</code> and trying to wrap my brain around how view controller transitions work, I think I've finally got the basics figured out. Thankfully I don't have to work with adaptation much yet. Baby steps.</p>
<p>How was your Friday? 🙂</p>
]]></content:encoded>
</item><item>

<link>http://jsorge.local/2018/05/19/i-stumbled-upon</link>
<guid ispermalink="false">5b03a67ecebcec05fe03fe5e</guid>
<pubdate>May 19, 2018</pubdate>
<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>I stumbled upon <a href="https://learnxinyminutes.com">this amazing resource</a> to help you learn a language or tool in a short amount of time.</p>
<p>It's a great reference for getting started on something unfamiliar.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
</item><item>

<link>http://jsorge.local/2018/05/17/the-money-ive</link>
<guid ispermalink="false">5b03a67ecebcec05fe03fe5e</guid>
<pubdate>May 17, 2018</pubdate>
<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The money I've spent on <a href="https://www.fastmail.com/?STKI=15614818">Fastmail</a> as my email provider is some of the best I've spent. I have 3 domains funneling there as well as all of my &quot;legacy&quot; email (iCloud &amp; Gmail) landing there too. Having only 1 email account setup on all my devices is really great.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
</item><item>

<link>http://jsorge.local/2018/05/17/thanks-to-twostrawss</link>
<guid ispermalink="false">5b03a67ecebcec05fe03fe5e</guid>
<pubdate>May 16, 2018</pubdate>
<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Thanks to <a href="https://www.hackingwithswift.com/about">@twostraws</a>'s Vapor book I found that I needed to register a middleware to handle stuff in the public folder. Once that was in my images and styles loaded instantly.</p>
<p>🎉🎉🎉</p>
]]></content:encoded>
</item><item>

<link>http://jsorge.local/2018/05/17/back-at-my</link>
<guid ispermalink="false">5b03a67ecebcec05fe03fe5e</guid>
<pubdate>May 16, 2018</pubdate>
<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Back at my Vapor 3 conversion for taphouse.io. I got the leaf errors figured out. 🎉</p>
<p>Next to get my assets linking properly in the Public folder.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
</item><item>

<link>http://jsorge.local/2018/05/16/vapor-rum-it</link>
<guid ispermalink="false">5b03a67ecebcec05fe03fe5e</guid>
<pubdate>May 15, 2018</pubdate>
<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><code>vapor rum</code>. It could be a long evening. At least the boys upstairs aren't screaming anymore.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
</item><item>

<link>http://jsorge.local/2018/05/16/tonights-project-after</link>
<guid ispermalink="false">5b03a67ecebcec05fe03fe5e</guid>
<pubdate>May 15, 2018</pubdate>
<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Tonight's project after the boys go to bed: Get my taphouse.io site up and running in Vapor 3 on a local Docker container. Extra credit will be given out if I'm able to also add nginx, and even more credit still if I can get it running on a server. Stay tuned.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
</item><item>

<link>http://jsorge.local/2018/05/16/the-days-when</link>
<guid ispermalink="false">5b03a67ecebcec05fe03fe5e</guid>
<pubdate>May 16, 2018</pubdate>
<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The days when I find something to write (even a short journal or microblog post) are days when I feel better. I don't know why that is.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
</item><item>

<link>http://jsorge.local/2018/05/16/im-calling-it</link>
<guid ispermalink="false">5b03a67ecebcec05fe03fe5e</guid>
<pubdate>May 15, 2018</pubdate>
<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>I’m calling it a night. Feeling somewhat defeated by these leaf templates. But I’ll figure it out. Eventually I’ll finish one of these side projects.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
</item><item>

<link>http://jsorge.local/2018/05/16/i-love-ichiro</link>
<guid ispermalink="false">5b03a67ecebcec05fe03fe5e</guid>
<pubdate>May 15, 2018</pubdate>
<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>I love Ichiro. He’s probably the only front office guy in baseball who would be out on the field celebrating an extra innings walk off win dresses in full uniform and batting gloves.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
</item><item>

<link>http://jsorge.local/2018/05/16/i-had-the</link>
<guid ispermalink="false">5b03a67ecebcec05fe03fe5e</guid>
<pubdate>May 15, 2018</pubdate>
<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>I had the site running on Vapor 2 last year. I'm <em>just</em> trying to update to 3 and the Leaf templating system is throwing errors I didn't see before. So I've gotta fix those before adapting for Docker. I don't expect even full credit at this point.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
</item><item>

<link>http://jsorge.local/2018/05/16/after-minutes-of</link>
<guid ispermalink="false">5b03a67ecebcec05fe03fe5e</guid>
<pubdate>May 15, 2018</pubdate>
<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>After 30 minutes of screaming, the boys are in bed, I've got an Old Fashioned, and I'm ready to tackle Vapor 3.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
</item><item>

<link>http://jsorge.local/2018/05/12/yup-my-boys</link>
<guid ispermalink="false">5b03a67ecebcec05fe03fe5e</guid>
<pubdate>May 11, 2018</pubdate>
<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Yup. My boys clogged a Froggy Potty.</p>
<!-- raw HTML omitted -->
]]></content:encoded>
</item><item>

<link>http://jsorge.local/2018/05/09/thor-ragnarok-is</link>
<guid ispermalink="false">5b03a67ecebcec05fe03fe5e</guid>
<pubdate>May 8, 2018</pubdate>
<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Thor Ragnarok is an incredibly rewatchable movie. Just so much fun.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
</item><item>

<link>http://jsorge.local/2018/05/09/just-saw-that</link>
<guid ispermalink="false">5b03a67ecebcec05fe03fe5e</guid>
<pubdate>May 8, 2018</pubdate>
<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Just saw that James Paxton threw a no hitter in Toronto. Way to go Big Maple! Go Mariners!</p>
]]></content:encoded>
</item><item>

<link>http://jsorge.local/2018/05/09/its-getting-increasingly</link>
<guid ispermalink="false">5b03a67ecebcec05fe03fe5e</guid>
<pubdate>May 9, 2018</pubdate>
<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>It’s getting increasingly common for us to go wake Atticus from nap and find him wearing a shirt for pants, having put his legs through the arms. I wonder if this kid just really wants skinny jeans?!</p>
]]></content:encoded>
</item><item>

<link>http://jsorge.local/2018/05/08/on-the-phone</link>
<guid ispermalink="false">5b03a67ecebcec05fe03fe5e</guid>
<pubdate>May 8, 2018</pubdate>
<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>On the phone with a senior Apple technical support guy and he did screen sharing with my iPhone. Never seen that before, but it's pretty cool.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
</item><item>
<title><![CDATA[My First Swift Package]]></title>
<link>http://jsorge.local/2018/05/07/my-first-swift-package</link>
<guid ispermalink="false">5b03a67ecebcec05fe03fe5e</guid>
<pubdate>May 6, 2018</pubdate>
<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>I’m embarking on phase 1 of my <a href="https://jsorge.net/2018/04/15/reconsidering-my-blogging-setup/">blog rethink</a> and have decided that whatever I do next will use <a href="http://textbundle.org/spec/">the textbundle spec</a> for file transport and storage. It will likely be some git repo or perhaps a Dropbox synced folder but all of the options that I’ve seen don’t strongly link a post together with assets. Textbundle solves that.</p>
<p>I think initially I might wrap Jekyll in something, so that the thing making the static site is really an implementation detail. The idea being that my server has an endpoint that would accept XML-RPC as well as micropub inputs, transform those to a textbundle and then build the static site from there.</p>
<p>So my first step was to download my posts stored on Ghost as well as my assets folder. I wanted a way to build textbundles out of these for easy migration. My first inclination was a Ruby script. I don’t know Ruby, so that became problematic from the start. So I turned to a more familiar language.</p>
<p>I made a Swift package called <a href="https://github.com/jsorge/textbundleify">textbundleify</a>, and the code is up on GitHub if you’re interested. It’s not polished in the slightest, but was a fun chance to try something new. It gets run from a directory containing Markdown files and if you give it a directory that contains pictures (or a directory of directories of pictures), it will embed linked images to the referenced textbundle.</p>
<p>I had to learn to use <code>Process</code> as well as <code>NSRegularExpression</code> (though I still don’t know how regular expressions really work). It was quite weird getting an <code>NSRange</code> for use on a Swift string, which only works on <code>String.Range</code> ranges. It was fun to put together over a few hours, and should do the migration trick I’m wanting.</p>
<p>The next step is to figure out the proper order of operations in converting textbundles (which Jekyll doesn’t support) to the structure that Jekyll does. I’ve still got Ruby learning on my horizon but at least there are <a href="https://twitter.com/timothyekl/status/991913298747572224">a couple</a> of <a href="https://twitter.com/soffes/status/992078081857761282">wonderful souls</a> who have offered some help to me if I need it.</p>
<p>Onward!</p>
]]></content:encoded>
</item><item>

<link>http://jsorge.local/2018/05/07/im-wanting-to</link>
<guid ispermalink="false">5b03a67ecebcec05fe03fe5e</guid>
<pubdate>May 7, 2018</pubdate>
<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>I'm wanting to get into scripting a bit more, and <a href="http://brettterpstra.com/2018/05/07/shell-tricks-quick-start-scripts/">this new trick from Brett Terpstra</a> will be a great way to spin up something new to try out.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
</item><item>

<link>http://jsorge.local/2018/05/07/im-super-sad</link>
<guid ispermalink="false">5b03a67ecebcec05fe03fe5e</guid>
<pubdate>May 7, 2018</pubdate>
<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>I'm super sad to learn that <a href="https://www.seattlemet.com/articles/2018/5/7/rain-shadow-meats-will-close-in-pioneer-square">Rain Shadow Meats is closing</a>. Our office just moved to Pioneer Square and I was looking forward to getting their wonderful porchetta sandwich from time to time.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
</item><item>

<link>http://jsorge.local/2018/05/07/044640</link>
<guid ispermalink="false">5b03a67ecebcec05fe03fe5e</guid>
<pubdate>May 6, 2018</pubdate>
<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>New post from jsorge.net: <a href="http://jsorge.net/2018/05/06/my-first-swift-package/">My First Swift Package</a></p>
]]></content:encoded>
</item><item>

<link>http://jsorge.local/2018/05/06/mariners-walk-off</link>
<guid ispermalink="false">5b03a67ecebcec05fe03fe5e</guid>
<pubdate>May 5, 2018</pubdate>
<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Mariners walk off! What a game!</p>
]]></content:encoded>
</item><item>

<link>http://jsorge.local/2018/05/05/im-writing-a</link>
<guid ispermalink="false">5b03a67ecebcec05fe03fe5e</guid>
<pubdate>May 5, 2018</pubdate>
<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>I'm writing a little thing that will take my markdown files and make them textbundles and want to embed images in the bundle.</p>
<p>Is a regular expression the best way to get any image names from that file?</p>
]]></content:encoded>
</item><item>

<link>http://jsorge.local/2018/05/04/i-just-realized</link>
<guid ispermalink="false">5b03a67ecebcec05fe03fe5e</guid>
<pubdate>May 4, 2018</pubdate>
<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>I just realized I've been a 1Password customer for 10 years now. It's easily in my pantheon of apps I couldn't live without.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
</item><item>

<link>http://jsorge.local/2018/05/03/star-wars-in</link>
<guid ispermalink="false">5b03a67ecebcec05fe03fe5e</guid>
<pubdate>May 2, 2018</pubdate>
<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><a href="https://youtu.be/o6XERmXsP-U">Star Wars in the style of Arrested Development</a> is the video we all need to see today.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
</item><item>

<link>http://jsorge.local/2018/05/03/sad-day-my</link>
<guid ispermalink="false">5b03a67ecebcec05fe03fe5e</guid>
<pubdate>May 3, 2018</pubdate>
<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Sad day: My Fluid app for GitHub is considered an “old browser&quot; and is starting to break on me. I emailed the developer of Fluid and hope to get a good response, but it hasn't been updated in <em>so long</em> that I'm not optimistic.</p>
<p>Any other good way to silo a web app on the Mac?</p>
]]></content:encoded>
</item><item>

<link>http://jsorge.local/2018/05/03/ok-i-got</link>
<guid ispermalink="false">5b03a67ecebcec05fe03fe5e</guid>
<pubdate>May 2, 2018</pubdate>
<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Ok, I got the site working locally. Victory! Next would be porting over my Ghost template to Jekyll. That's a battle for another day.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
</item><item>

<link>http://jsorge.local/2018/05/03/im-trying-to</link>
<guid ispermalink="false">5b03a67ecebcec05fe03fe5e</guid>
<pubdate>May 2, 2018</pubdate>
<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>I'm trying to get a Jekyll instance running locally and I keep running into Ruby and Gems issues. I've only used Ruby for Cocoapods and the Gems concept is all new to me. Maybe this isn't the blog engine for me.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
</item><item>
<title><![CDATA[View Controllers Make Crummy Navigators]]></title>
<link>http://jsorge.local/2018/05/02/view-controllers-make-crummy-navigators</link>
<guid ispermalink="false">5b03a67ecebcec05fe03fe5e</guid>
<pubdate>May 1, 2018</pubdate>
<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>My fellow iOS developers, we have a problem. We’ve been led astray by Apple. Don’t get me wrong, iOS is great. I love writing code in Swift (and Objective-C!). I’m a fan of Xcode too. And UIKit really makes a lot of really powerful things quite easy. But allow me this hot take: View controllers should never have to deal with navigation.</p>
<p>There’s a long running joke about MVC actually standing for <a href="https://duckduckgo.com/?q=massive+view+controller&amp;t=osx&amp;ia=qa">massive view controllers</a> and navigation is a key reason. Even a relatively simple view controller with a couple of possible destinations, using storyboards and segues, needs to implement methods that could grow to be dozens of lines long and end up knowing about the implementation details of view controllers that come after them.</p>
<p>What are we to do? There must be some way that can keep our view controllers clean of navigation <em>and</em> doesn’t fight the UIKit frameworks completely, right?</p>
<p>There is!</p>
<p>If we treat view controllers like functional pieces, we can expose a small interface to interact with them and use delegation to get stuff out. Here’s a trivial example:</p>
<pre><code>protocol PeopleViewControllerDelegate: AnyObject {
    func personSelected(_ person: Person, from viewController: PeopleViewController)
}

final class PeopleViewController: UIViewController, UITableViewDelegate {
    var delegate: PeopleViewControllerDelegate?
    private var people: [People]?

    func configureWithPeople(_ people: [Person]) {
        self.people = people
        // fill a table with people
    }

    func tableView(_ tableView: UITableView, didSelectRowAt indexPath: IndexPath) {
        // find the person
        self.delegate?.personSelected(person, from: self)
    }
}
</code></pre>
<p>This view controller (while grossly incomplete) gets configured with an array of people that will fill a table view. Tap on a row and the view controller’s job is done. It hands off the person to its delegate. What happens next is out of its hands. Perhaps we’ll show a detail screen, but maybe it’s just an API call and this view controller gets dismissed. Our <code>PeopleViewController</code> doesn’t know, and doesn’t care. Kind of great, right?</p>
<p>This begs the question of <em>what</em> exactly is the delegate? I’ve come to really like the <a href="http://khanlou.com/2015/01/the-coordinator/">coordinator pattern</a> myself. I like having objects whose specific responsibility it is to manage the flow of my app (or just a given object’s slice of the app).</p>
<p>There are some things that you’ll have to give up, of course. Storyboard segues are a non-starter in this pattern. This means that there are large swaths of sample code (Apple’s and others’) that you’ll need to learn to either ignore or translate into this pattern.</p>
<p>So let’s trim down the size of our view controllers. Let’s narrow their scopes of responsibility, and in turn we’ll get code that is more maintainable and easier to reason about. I think we will all be better off.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
</item><item>

<link>http://jsorge.local/2018/05/02/the-only-reason</link>
<guid ispermalink="false">5b03a67ecebcec05fe03fe5e</guid>
<pubdate>May 1, 2018</pubdate>
<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The only reason it's not insane for parents to pick up after their kids day after day after day is that they don't expect different results.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
</item><item>

<link>http://jsorge.local/2018/05/02/reminder-to-my</link>
<guid ispermalink="false">5b03a67ecebcec05fe03fe5e</guid>
<pubdate>May 2, 2018</pubdate>
<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Reminder to my future self: setting the <code>delegate</code> property on a <code>UINavigationController</code> subclass doesn't always do what I think it will do. In the case of the <code>MFMessageComposeViewController</code>, I needed to set the <code>messageComposeDelegate</code> instead.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
</item><item>

<link>http://jsorge.local/2018/05/02/045845</link>
<guid ispermalink="false">5b03a67ecebcec05fe03fe5e</guid>
<pubdate>May 1, 2018</pubdate>
<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>New post from jsorge.net: <a href="http://jsorge.net/2018/05/01/view-controllers-make-crummy-navigators/">View Controllers Make Crummy Navigators</a></p>
]]></content:encoded>
</item><item>

<link>http://jsorge.local/2018/04/30/im-having-this</link>
<guid ispermalink="false">5b03a67ecebcec05fe03fe5e</guid>
<pubdate>Apr 30, 2018</pubdate>
<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>I'm having this really weird and aggravating problem where some Apple Music songs will not play on my iPhone X but they will play on other devices. Hoping Apple's support can get to the bottom of it. I’ve restarted the phone a few times to no avail.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
</item><item>

<link>http://jsorge.local/2018/04/28/ive-totally-bought</link>
<guid ispermalink="false">5b03a67ecebcec05fe03fe5e</guid>
<pubdate>Apr 28, 2018</pubdate>
<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>I've totally bought in on the <a href="https://www.si.com/nfl/2018/03/03/shaquem-griffin-bench-press-one-hand-nfl-combine">Shaquem Griffin hype train.</a> I'm stoked to see him in Seattle. Go Hawks!</p>
]]></content:encoded>
</item></channel></rss>